本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译创作
欢迎爱好者加入我们  www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Cherie_1211  微辣不要青椒  meggiesong   一校：进化的时间轴
二校：可乐嘻嘻  监制：可乐嘻嘻  后期：LP_LadiesMan
■
判多米尼克・特若图
Dominic Toretto.
二十五年有期徒刑
You are hereby sentenced to serve 25 years to life
收押于隆波克最高警备监狱
at the Lompoc Maximum Security Prison system
不得提前假释
without the possibility of early parole.
速度与激情
隆波克囚车车祸现场连线--
FBI
联邦执法
突 发 新 闻
执法部门全力搜索三名逃犯
前联邦探员畏罪潜逃
搜捕三名逃犯
后 续 报 道
越狱：
唯一逃逸者：多米尼克・特若图
目前据我们的了解
Here's what we know so far.
这是一起光天化日猖狂越狱案发现场
This is all the aftermath of a daring, daylight breakout.
车内共有二十六名重罪犯
There were 26 high-risk inmates being transferred...
车上所有人员都已归案
where everyone on board has been accounted for,
唯独多米尼克・特若图不见踪影
except for one, Dominic Toretto.
下午的事故经过精心策划
Police have just released the identity
未导致任何人员伤亡
of the man they believe to have orchestrated the shocking escape
警方认定劫囚车者身份
that amazingly resulted in no fatalities this afternoon.
他是前联邦调查员布莱恩・欧康纳
He is former federal agent, Brian O'Conner.
今晚注定被这三个逃犯搅得鸡犬不宁
A fierce manhunt is underway for three fugitives tonight.
各级警力加入搜捕队伍
Multiple federal and local agencies have joined forces
搜寻多米尼克・特若图
in the search for Dominic Toretto
和其同伙布莱恩・欧康纳及米亚・特若图
and his accomplices Brian O'Conner and Mia Toretto.
尽管举国之力都在尽力搜捕
But despite every eye in the country looking for them
特若图和欧康纳仍下落不明
where Toretto and O'Conner are now is anyone's guess.
是这里没错吧
It's got to be it, right?
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
别紧张  伙计们
Easy, friends.
她是自己人
She's with me.
米亚
Mia.
文森
Vince.
臭小子
Buster.
来吧
Come on.
多姆来了吗
Dom here yet?
没
No.
上次有他消息是什么时候
When was the last time you heard from him?
几星期前  像是在厄瓜多尔
A couple of weeks ago. Up in Ecuador somewhere.
-感觉怎么样  -什么怎么样
- How does it feel? - What's that?
捕人变成被捕
To be on the other side of a wanted poster?
他会现身的
He'll show up.
多姆的?
Dom's?
小家伙该睡觉了
Time for bed little one.
我能带他去吗
Can I bring him?
当然
Of course.
晚安
Good night.
不好意思
Excuse me, sorry.
为什么来里约  文森
Why Rio, Vince?
你是说在你把洛杉矶搞得一团糟以后吗
You mean after you screwed everything up in LA?
无奈落脚在南美
Ended up free-falling through South America, you know,
一路躲躲藏藏
hitting every hellhole on the way down.
要不是为罗莎  还得继续逃
Would have kept on going if not for Rosa.
他知道吗
Does he know?
听着
So, listen.
现在有个活儿
There is a job coming up.
我希望多姆也能在这  但是
I was hoping Dom was going to be here by now
这次很简单  没他也能做
but this one is clean enough we can do it without him.
大买卖  几辆高端车  目标简单
It's a good gig. Couple of high-end cars, easy targets.
一个熟人招了些伙计打算干这票
Guy I know is putting together a team to swipe them.
就是还缺几个人手
Just need a few more willing bodies.
我不知道
I don't know.
那批车路过这里
Look, the way the car scene is down here
我们只需快速把它们装卸就能拿大钱
we can unload them quick and get top dollar.
这钱赚的容易
It's easy money.
就我看来
And from where I'm sitting,
你俩都可以捞上一笔
it looks like you both could use the payday.
你在看什么
What are you reading?
旅游指南
Travel guide.
是吗
Yeah?
东京
Tokyo.
莫斯科
Moscow.
果阿邦
Goa.
这些地方都什么相同点
You want to know what all of these places have in common?
什么
Huh?
不能引渡
No extradition.
走啦
Here we go.
借过  伙计
Excuse me, buddy.
好了
Okay.
找到了
Hey, we've found them.
从后面数第二间
Yeah, second-to-the-last freighter.
这是什么
What is it?
药品管理局标签  这车被查封了
DEA tags. These cars have been seized.
看  谁来了
Look who showed up.
天啊  真高兴你没事
God, I'm so happy you're okay.
我告诉你们要低调行事
I thought I told you to lay low.
我弹尽粮绝了  不得不做
Been running on fumes. Had to make a call.
别扯淡了  我们只有两分钟
Hey! Quit talking. We only got the two-minute window.
走  文森
Let's go, Vince.
我要那辆GT40[福特一跑车型号]
I'm taking the GT40.
女士优先
Ladies first.
这车更适合我
This car suits me better.
待会见  宝贝
See you, baby.
没关系  我们都去一个地方
It's okay... we're all going to the same place.
到那儿再把车弄回来
We'll get the car there.
计划有变  等我电话
Change of plans. Wait for my call.
放下去
Let's go!
她去哪
Where is she going?
她要去哪
Where is she going? Hey!
我们被劫了  无论如何别让火车停下来
We're being robbed! Whatever happens, don't stop the train!
快追那女的
Go after the girl!
快
Hurry up!
门禁卡  快拿门禁卡
Access card! Get the access card!
该死
Shit.
多姆  那有个桥
Bridge! There is a bridge!
行李车厢没人
Luggage car is clear.
不许动
Freeze!
该死
Oh, Shit!
不得不干一票  啊
You had to make a call, huh?
什么烂活儿  欧康纳
Shitty call, O'Conner.
烂活儿
Shitty call.
你们今天可惹了不少麻烦
You two stirred up quite a bit of trouble today.
我的人死了三个
Three of my men dead.
三个药品管理局的人也挂了
Three DEA agents along with them.
当然
Of course,
做生意有得有失
this is business and sometimes things go astray.
我只关心车
All I care about is the car.
告诉我在哪  就放你们走
Tell me where it is, and I'll let you go.
纯属扯淡
This roofing plastic says you're full of shit.
我不知道在你们那里是怎么做生意的
I don't know how you guys do business in your part of the world,
但在里约
but here in Rio,
所有人都清楚他们的对手是谁
I like it when all parties know what they're up against.
好笑
That's funny.
井水不犯河水
Because it goes both ways.
那个
You know,
我听说你妹妹很漂亮
I hear your sister is very beautiful.
就算她藏到天涯海角
Wherever she hides
我也能找到她
I Will find her.
美国逃犯在火车抢劫中
The American fugitives killed
杀了三名药管局官员
three DEA agents during a train robbery...
警方警告市民逃犯带有枪支并极其危险
...Police warn they are armed and extremely dangerous.
任何人有嫌犯任何消息  请及时与警方联系
Anyone with information should contact law enforcement immediately...
米亚
Mia?
你还好吗
You okay?
还行  你呢
Yeah, you all right?
不愧是特若图家的
Just like a Toretto.
文森呢
Where's Vince?
问得好
That's a good question.
他会来的
He'll be here.
新闻里都是我们的消息
Guys, we're all over the news.
他们把三个药管局官员的死
They're blaming us for the
怪到我们头上
killing of those DEA agents on the train.
我们又成了头号通缉犯
Which means we just jumped to the top of the wanted list.
联邦探子哪儿都是
The feds have got to show everyone their agents are off limits
他们会派最厉害的人马
and they're going to send their best guys.
我们得离开这里
We got to get out of here.
有件事可以肯定
One thing we know for sure
他们想要这车
is that they wanted this car.
车里有鬼
Because something is in it.
我们查清楚  就知道对手是谁了
If we find out what it is, we'll know what we're up against.
听着
All right, listen up!
我们追捕的是专业车手
The men we're after are professional runners.
他们喜欢速度  而且敢铤而走险
They like speed and are guaranteed to go down the hardest possible way
所有要保证弹药充足
so make sure you got your funderwear on.
找到后一个不落全部带来回
We find them, we take them as a team, and we bring them back.
最重要一点  绝不能让他们弄到车
And above all else, we don't ever, ever let them get into cars.
据事发近10小时了  开始行动
Crime scene is 10 hours old and counting, men. Let's go hunting.
霍布斯警官  我是警察局长  齐诺・阿米达
Agente Hobbs! Chief of Police, Jono Alemeida.
卢克
Luke.
你手下的殉职  我很遗憾
Sorry to hear about the loss of your men.
就两个人值得这么大动干戈吗
Is all this really necessary to apprehend two men?
这两个人来头不小
Let me tell you something about these two men.
一个是前联邦警官
One is a former federal officer,
做了五年卧底
been in deep cover for five years.
对我们的行动了如指掌
He knows every way you're going to come for him.
另一个是职业罪犯  两次越狱
The other one is a professional criminal, escaped prison twice,
大半生都在躲像你我这样的人
spent half his life on the run avoiding folks like you.
如果有什么可以帮忙
Well, if there's anything we can do to help the DSS...
两件事  一  我需要个翻译
Two things. One, I need a translator.
我们公关部有很多...
We have plenty in the public relations department.
埃莉娜・奈维思
Elena Neves.
-是个巡警吗  -没错
- A patrol officer? - You heard me.
为什么  其他人更有经验
But why? We have many more experienced people.
我喜欢她的笑
I like her smile.
第二件是什么
What's the second thing?
别他妈挡我的道
Stay the fuck out of my way.
布莱恩
Brian. Hm?
我有事要告诉你
I have something I have to tell you.
靠
God damn.
真够乱的
What a mess!
你去哪了
Where you been, man?
你怎么说话呢
You better check that tone.
你最好快回答我
And you just better answer the goddamn question.
住手  你们两个
Stop it! Both of you.
你去哪了  文森
Where were you, Vince?
贫民窟的混混都在打听你
Guys all over the favelas asking about you.
非要弄清你的下落才让我脱身
Couldn't get out of there without leading them straight to you.
弄完了才来
Had to wait them out.
放狗屁
That is such horseshit
这次你揽的活儿  我们是为你卖命
That was your job, and those were your guys! Hey!
够了  欧康纳
Hey! Enough, O'Conner!
他说没做就没做
If he said he didn't do it, he didn't do it.
一边儿待着去
Go walk it off.
我愿意在贵国扩大我公司的业务
Look, I would love to expand my operations into your countries
但老实说  你行事风格太过暴力
but, quite frankly, your business methods are too violent.
我给你讲个故事
Let me tell you a true story.
五百年前  西葡两国殖民者来到这
Five hundred years ago, the Portuguese and the Spanish came here,
都想把这里收入囊中
each trying to get the country from their natives.
西班牙人带着长枪短
The Spaniards arrived, guns blazing,
誓要证明谁是老大
determined to prove who was boss.
但全被土著人杀了
The natives killed every single Spaniard.
我个人更欣赏葡萄牙人的方法
Personally, I prefer the methods of the Portuguese.
他们奉上礼物
They came bearing gifts.
镜子  剪刀  毛毯
Mirrors, scissors, trinkets.
一些土著人自己没有的东西
Things that the natives couldn't get on their own,
想用这些东西
but to continue receiving them,
就得听命于葡萄牙人
they had to work for the Portuguese.
所以现在巴西人都说葡萄牙语
And that's why all Brazilians speak Portuguese today.
如果你想以暴制人
Now, if you dominate the people with violence,
最终他们会反抗
they will eventually fight
因为他们没什么输不起的
back because they have nothing to lose.
这是关键
And that's the key.
我去贫民区施舍点东西
I go into the favelas and give them something to lose.
电  自来水  学校教室
Electricity, running water, school rooms for their kids.
让他们尝到了生活的甜头
And for that taste of a better life,
我就控制了他们
I own them.
各位干杯
Gentlemen.
抱歉打扰一下
I apologize for the interruption.
雷耶斯老大  有事跟您报告
Senior Reyes, may I speak with you?
我们找到他们了
We've found them.
失陪一下
Pardon me, gentlemen.
真希望我没看到
Almost wish I didn't see that.
真希望
Almost.
等等  多姆
Wait, Dom.
当时米亚在火车上
Mia was on that train.
我妹在车上
My sister!
我不知道  我不会伤害她
I didn't know. I wouldn't do anything to hurt her.
你自己接的生意
You set up the deal!
我以为只是偷车而已
I thought the job was for the cars.
我之前不知道
I didn't know.
他们只想要芯片
All they want is the chip.
操
Damn!
事先你怎么不说清楚
You should've come clean.
你们在吵什么
What's going on out here?
没什么
Nothing.
拜托  多姆  把芯片给我  我给他们
Please, Dom, just let me have the chip. I can take this to them.
我拿给雷耶斯  一切都结了
They'll give it to Reyes and set things right.
滚
Get out.
什么
What?
滚
Get out!
你从来不听我的
You never listen to me.
那时我说他是个条子你不信
Not when I told you he was a cop,
现在还不信我
and not now.
你从不相信我
You never trust me and
看看我们现在
look where it's gotten us.
看看我们帮派
Look at our family now.
我有家不能回
I can't go home!
看你妹妹过的什么日子
Your sister is stuck in this life!
莉迪呢  多姆
Where's Letty, Dom?
莉迪：多姆女友  速4中被毒枭灭口
莉迪呢
Where's Letty?
离子切割机
Plasma cutter.
威尔克斯  给我一份附近五十英里以内
Wilkes, I want a list of every place within 50 miles
运送压缩气罐的地点名单
that distributes compressed gas tanks.
把证物袋给我
Pass me that manifest.
奈维思警官  怎么才来
Officer Neves. Been waiting for you.
-是你点名要我  -对
- You asked for me? - I did.
为什么
May I ask why?
我的笑容没那么好看
My smile is not that great.
你丈夫是位警官  在贫民区被枪杀
Your husband was an officer who was gunned down in the favela.
六个月后你振作起来加入了警队
Six months later, you upped and joined the force.
你能保持干劲
You're motivated.
而且 在里约你是绝对不会被收买的人
Plus, I figure you're the only one in Rio who cannot be bought.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
-是的  -当然
- Yes. - Of course I am.
喜忧参半
Good news, bad news.
说来听听
You know I like my dessert first.
我按你说的检查了铁路线
Back-checked the rail line like you asked.
发现几个他们卸车的痕迹
Found a couple of spots where they unloaded the cars.
一条往西
One set of tracks headed west
一直到主道才消失
until it hit the main highway, then disappeared.
另一条往东
But another set of tracks headed east.
轴距一百七十英寸  轮胎印宽半英寸
A 107-inch wheelbase, eight-and-a-half-inch tread.
是GT40吗  从货单上失踪的那辆
The GT40 that was missing from the manifest.
留了几公里车印
Followed the trail a couple of miles.
这车很容易留印
Pretty easy in this scrub.
只要走动没法不留痕
Can't move without leaving a sign.
把那该死的痕迹照给我
Give me the damn veggies.
后来车开到硬地  胎印就没了
The ground rolls into a hardpack and we lost that track, too.
也不一定
Not necessarily.
那条路穿过山丘通到贫民区
That road heads up through the hills into the favelas.
几年前被暴雨重开了
Couple of years ago, it was washed out by a storm.
经过那一公里车胎会粘上泥
It's all dirt a mile from where you were.
往那边走  就能追踪到他们痕迹了
If they headed that way, we'll pick up their tracks there.
有备而来啊
You come prepared.
我干劲十足
I'm motivated.
好了
All right, then.
我们这就去找
Let's find ourselves a car.
你觉得怎样
What do you think?
这芯片绝对不简单
Well, it's definitely a custom chip.
看边上这些输入数据的菜单
Look at all these side menus here for data entry.
看看这个
Let's check this one.
看  同一幢大楼  每周一单
Look at that. Same building, same order every week.
交易时间表
It's a delivery schedule.
这是什么
What's this?
毒品吗
Drugs?
不  交易量
No. That's a dealer pack.
看  他们用这个货量来算钱
See, most major players, they weigh their money
这样就不用一点点的数了
so they don't have to constantly count it.
那是四十九千克
Right there, that's 49 kilos.
在二十年代值一百万
49 kilos is a million in twenties.
你是说每批货值一千万
You're saying each one of these shipments is worth 10 million dollars?
这才像话
I thought so.
那是什么
So what is that?
一亿钞票的金库吗
A 100-million plus in cash houses?
这是查不到的交易凭证
That's how he keeps it off the grid.
雷耶斯不是傻子
I think it's safe to say that Reyes
这东西不能落入他手
is smart to want this back.
芯片上就是他的交易网
It's his whole network right there, just laid out on a chip.
威尔克斯和富斯科去中路
Wilkes, Fusco, up the middle.
迈克  乔托  从北边上
Mac, Chato, flank north.
我呢
What about me?
待在这
Stay here.
去那边
Go that way!
另外两个翻墙了
The other two went over the wall!
快  快
Come on, go! Go!
趴下
Get on the ground.
我抓到特若图了  距4个房区...
I got Toretto. Four blocks north of your...
他们知道你们是警察
They already know who you are.
我们走
Let's go.
你还好吗
You okay here?
很好  谢谢
Yeah. I'm good. Thank you.
他们会把我们三个一锅端
They're going to be looking for the three of us together now.
我们得分开走
We need to split up.
你和米亚往南走  我把他们引开
You and Mia head south, I'll lead them away.
不
No.
多姆说得对
Dom is right.
这次我们侥幸逃脱  那下次呢
Look how lucky we just got. What happens next time?
我们只能分头行动
We have no choice but to split up.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我失去过一次亲人
I already lost my family once.
我不想再失去了
I'm not going through that again.
-你开玩笑吗  -不是
- Are you kidding me? - No.
我哪也不去  好吗
I'm not going anywhere. Okay?
多姆
Dom?
答应我  我们一直在一起
Promise me we stick together.
我答应
I promise.
我们家族要添丁了
Our family just got bigger.
事有蹊跷
Something doesn't add up.
特若图和欧康纳  能走却没走
Toretto and O'Conner. They stay when they're supposed to run,
他们偷了东西  弃之不理
they steal gas then give it away?
还杀了三个联邦官员
Now they're killing federal agents?
没道理
It doesn't make any sense.
道理在这
Here's what makes sense.
这些人都是逃犯
All these guys are is names on a list.
他们一出现  我们就拿下
They come up, we take them down.
不用报告  打光全部子弹
Not a phone call more, not a bullet less.
威尔克斯  有进展吗
Wilkes, we get anything?
标准取证
Standard forensics.
鞋印  头发
Shoe prints. Hair and fiber.
车上尽是指纹
Prints are all over the car.
还有吗
Anything else?
我们根据车的编码查到了用户信息
Yeah, we tracked the owner off the vehicle ID.
几个空壳公司
There are a couple of shell companies in between,
最后发现这几家公司都属于
but we finally traced it back to
投资人埃尔南・雷耶斯的电力集团
a corporation owned by an investor down here named Hernan Reyes.
投资人
Investor?
里约所有的非法交易  雷耶斯都有份
If there is anything illegal happening in Rio, Reyes is involved.
这样我们也要插一脚了
Okay, then so are we.
他和我们有瓜葛了
If he could get us any closer to our guys,
那就查查他
I want everything on him.
乔托  去楼顶守着
Chato, you're on the roof.
防止有人返回报复
I want you on overwatch in case somebody comes back for something.
迈克  跟踪监视雷耶斯
Mac, give me a cross-check on Reyes, full specs.
看他见了什么人
If he goes to the john,
握了几次手
I want to know how many times he shakes it.
知道了头儿
You got it, boss.
威尔克斯  富斯科
Wilkes, Fusco!
来把这堆废铁组装起来
Let's put all this mess back together.
那得费不少工夫
That's going to take a while.
那就赶紧的吧
Then you better get started.
他们凭白无故不会卸车
They were taking this car apart for a reason.
重新装起来看少了什么
Let's put it back together and find out what's missing.
多姆  你还记得你父亲什么样吗
Hey, Dom, what do you remember about your father?
我父亲
My father.
他以前
He used to...
他以前会每周日做完礼拜后做烧烤
He used to have a barbecue every Sunday after church.
邻里街坊都来吃
For anybody in the neighborhood.
如果我们没去做礼拜  就没烤肉吃
If you didn't go to church, you didn't get any barbecue.
每天白天他都在店里
Every single day he was in the shop,
每个晚上他都在厨房桌子上
and every single night, he was at the kitchen table with Mia,
辅导米亚做家庭作业
helping her with her homework.
就算她睡了  他也会再看几个小时
Even after she went to sleep, he'd stay up for a few more hours
学下一章明天再辅导她
so he could learn the next chapter and help her the next day.
我记得我父亲的所有事
I remember everything about my father.
所有事
Everything.
算了
That's just it.
我一点都不了解我爸
I don't remember shit about my dad.
我不记得他大吼大叫
I don't remember him yelling.
不记得他的笑容
I don't remember him smiling.
说实话
To be honest with you,
我都不太记得他长什么样
I don't even remember what the hell he looked like.
我所有的记忆里
I don't remember. He just...
他总是不在
He was just never there.
你不会像他一样的  布莱恩
You ain't going to be like that, Brian.
我们不能逃下去了  多姆
We can't keep running, Dom.
我们得金盆洗手
We got to get out.
立刻马上
We got to get out now.
你说得对
You're right.
我们这么做
Here's how we're going to do it.
用这个东西
We're going to use this.
干上最后一票
We're going do one last job.
搞到雷耶斯所有的钱
We're going to take all of Reyes' money.
一个铜板都不剩
Every dime of it,
然后永远
and disappear.
消失
Forever.
新护照
New passports.
新生活   再不东躲西藏
New lives with no more looking over our shoulder.
我们就自由了
And we're just going to buy our freedom.
没错
That's right.
你想过没
You realize
我们这次是要对抗里约的老大
we're talking about going up against the most powerful guy in all of Rio?
是的  我知道
Yes, we are.
那么就要招兵买马
Then we're going to need a team.
那我们好好想想 都招谁
Let's run through the bases real quick. Who do we got?
首先  一个多面手
First we're going to need a chameleon.
处处深藏不露
Someone who can blend in anywhere.
还有呢
What else?
大忽悠
A fast talker.
一张嘴走遍天下
Someone who can bullshit their way out of anything.
我认识一个
I got that.
他们有很多监控设备
This guy is going to have a lot of surveillance.
需要一个人搞定这些监控
We're going to need someone who is good with circuits.
除了监控
And with those circuits,
雷耶斯一定有个保险箱
Reyes is going to have wells.
还需要人手破解保险箱
We're going to need guys to punch through those walls.
然后呢
What else?
火力掩护
Utilities and weapons.
一个不俱危险的
Someone who ain't afraid to throw down.
全能型后援
Someone to back up every position.
还需要别的吗
Yeah, what else do we need?
最重要的
Most importantly,
两个稳妥的车手
we're going to need two precision drivers.
关键时刻不会掉链子
Guys that don't crack under pressure.
永不放弃
Guys that never lose.
车手  你我都有数了
You know we got that.
不是吧
Aw, hell, no!
这次还真是兴师动众
I see they really scraped the bottom of the barrel, huh?
你这货都来了  那一定是
I guess they did, since your ass is here.
你打算什么时候把马丁・路德・金的车开回来
When are you going to give Martin Luther King his car back?
马丁・路德・金:为黑人争取平等权利的倡导者
等你拿来瑞克・詹姆斯的夹克再说
As soon as you give Rick James his jacket back.
瑞克・詹姆斯:上世纪七八十年代著名音乐人
过的怎么样  老兄
What's up, man?
长腿妹
Sexy legs, baby girl.
啥时候伺候哥一下
What time do they open?
在我扣下扳机之后
They open the same time as I pull this trigger.
还想让我伺候你吗
Want me to open them?
告诉过你这个美腿妞儿不好惹
I told you the skinny chick had balls.
看起来她已经自己找到乐子了
Looks like she started the party without us.
兄弟  西班牙语怎么骂人
Hey, anybody can talk shit in Spanish, homie.
这哥们说什么呢
What's this guy saying?
长得丑说啥语都没用
Ugly is still ugly in Spanish or in English.
-这两个小丑是谁  -马戏团来的吧
- Who are these clowns, man? - Circus clowns.
我还以为巴西斗鸡犯法呢
I thought cockfights were illegal in Brazil.
都互相认识了吧
I see you all have met.
你叫我来里约的时候
You know when you called me to come to Rio
我以为是比这更有意思的事儿呢
I assumed it would be for something more exciting than this.
来了伙计
Look at this guy.
-好久不见  -想死你了
- Long time. - I missed you, man.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
兄弟  啥事
Brother. What's up?
认识一下  这是泰基
Yo, check this out. This is Tej.
东海岸最厉害的万能电工
Best circuit man on the East Coast.
我的老朋友罗曼・皮尔斯
And this is my boy, Roman Pearce.
老交情了  我在少管所认识的
We go way back, I met this guy in juvie.
迈阿密那票就是和他联手干的
I pulled that job with him in Miami.
久仰大名
I've heard about you.
选对人了
Nice digs.
是  没有别人了
Yeah, well, the Ritz was sold out.
那现在是什么情况
So what's this all about, Dom?
你折腾我们横跨了半个地球为了什么
Yeah, man, why did you drag us halfway around the world?
有笔买卖
Because we got a job.
目标名叫埃尔南・雷耶斯
All right, so our target's name is Hernan Reyes.
这里的毒枭
And he runs the drug scene down here.
他从未落马  因为不留书面字据
He's never been busted because he doesn't leave a paper trail.
那就是说钱不通过银行
No paper trail means no banks.
存在现金仓库里
And no banks means cash houses.
说得对  总共十家金库
That's right. Ten of them, to be exact.
分散在城内
Spread throughout the city.
我们要把钱都拿走
And we're going to hit them all.
所有吗
All of them?
对
All of them.
太疯狂了
That sounds crazy.
叫我们来异国他乡
You bring us to a whole other country
还要去抢劫这里的老大
so we can rob the dude who runs it?
我以为只是笔买卖
I thought this was business.
但更像是私人恩怨
Sounds personal to me.
就这事吗
Is that what this is?
我爱你们大家
I got love for y'all,
但是私人恩怨的生意真的不好做
but personal ain't good business.
我觉得我干不了
I can't do this, homie.
这次生意是个一亿美元的大单
So what we're talking about is $100 million.
你说什么
You say what?
你看  我有时候想得比较多
Hundred... See, sometimes I be over thinking, man,
可能是  我们刚认识  但是
and I know we just met, but you just, kind of, got to...
对  一亿  拿多少
That's right, $100 million, and everything we take,
就分多少
we split even.
每人一千一百万
That's a little over $11 million apiece.
砸死我吧
I am down.
我加入
I'm in.
一千一百万
Eleven million.
像成千上万女人对我投怀送抱
Sounds like a whole lot of vaginal activity to me.
你不可能同时抢十家
You can't pull off 10 heists on the same mark.
完全没可能
You just can't.
对  我们抢了第一个
As soon as we hit the first one,
他们就会拼命保护其他几个
they're going to do everything they can to protect the rest.
没错
Exactly.
都别动
Nobody move!
都在这了
That's all of it.
你们死定了
You a dead man.
你们都死定了
You're all dead men!
你们无处可藏
You don't have a place to hide.
谁要藏了
Who's hiding?
你们疯了吗
Are you crazy?
都疯了吗
知道这是谁的地方吗
Do you know whose house this is?
知道偷的是谁的钱吗
Whose money are you stealing?
我们不偷
We ain't stealing it.
给你老板带个话  告诉他谁干的
You tell your boss exactly who did this.
告诉他这还不算完
Tell him there's more coming.
好啦
Voila.
发动它
Turn it over.
运转正常  没问题
She's running on all eight. Checks out fine.
接着找
Keep looking.
头儿  如果少了什么东西我们会知道的
Boss, if something was missing, we'd know.
这东西出现在这种跑车上太低级
It's a goddamn shame putting bullshit like that on a classic.
还可以用
You may as well slap neon lights on it.
他们把芯片拿走了
They took the chip.
警方监视器发现情况
We got a hit on the police scanner.
黎布朗一处仓库发生武装抢劫
Armed robbery at a house in Leblon.
地址核查得出
Address cross-checks against property
正是雷耶斯公司财产
owned by one of Hernan Reyes' corporations.
好吧  如果是我们追捕的那伙人
All right, if that's our guys
一定是芯片上的内容引导他们去的那里
then whatever was on that chip led them directly to that house.
肯定是他们
It's them, for sure.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为在里约没人傻到去抢雷耶斯
Because no one else in Rio is stupid enough to rob Reyes.
给我解释
Explain.
他们侵入了黎布朗的仓库
They invaded the Leblon house.
谁
Who invaded?
火车上的那些人
The men from the train.
他们拿走多少钱
How much did they take?
一分也没拿
They didn't take anything.
他们把钱烧了
They burned it!
他们烧了我的钱
They burned my money?
是的  还说这还不算完
Yes. And said there's more coming.
好吧
Okay...
那么
Then this...
我们这么做
...is what we're going to do.
清理所有金库
Clean the houses.
我要那笔钱在
I want that money under lock and key...
一小时内锁好
...within an hour.
明白吗
Understand?
明白
Understood.
一号出动了
Number One is on the move, man.
二号上路了
Two is on the move.
我跟上了
I got mine.
五号盯上
I got eyes on Five.
你们都说  他会把钱转移到某处
I know y'all said they were consolidating the money somewhere, but,
但是你绝没想到这一点
y'all ain't going to believe this.
警察署
难度增加了
Well, this job just got a lot harder.
他既然能把钱放到警察局
If he's moving it into a police station
说明他肯定认识高层人物
he's got some serious brass in his pocket.
看起来我们要提前收场了
Looks like this is going to be a shorter trip than I thought...
太对了  这活儿没法干
Hell, yeah, we can't do this.
没法干  或者说不该干
"Can't"'? You mean, "Shouldn't."
我觉得没什么影响
I think this doesn't change a thing.
按计划进行
I say we stick to the plan.
你说什么
You say what?
这破活已经从不可能
This just went from Mission: Impossible
变成疯子才去做
to Mission: In-freaking-sanity.
随便吧伙计
Whatever, man.
我不是害怕  就是提醒你们一下
I ain't scared, I'm just letting you all know,
进去就是疯子
going in that building is crazy.
这我知道
I got this.
几点发生的抢劫
What time was the robbery?
十一点左右
11:00.
找到了
Here we go.
放大
Enhance it.
脸被遮住了
Their faces are covered.
面部识别
Run it through FRS.
好啊  王八蛋
Well, hello, you son of a bitch.
威尔克斯
Wilkes!
把特若图和欧康纳关系网里的照片
Run the photos of known associates of Toretto and O'Conner
和最近两周入关巴西的人进行比对
against customs entries into Brazil in the last two weeks.
检查海陆空
Check planes, trains, boats,
和除了航天飞机的一切运输设备
everything short of the goddamn space shuttle.
他们能换个名字  但是换不了脸
They can change their names but they can't change their faces.
他们一定在计划什么
Something big is going down.
这是辆一九七零年的Charger[著名肌肉车]
That's a 1970 Charger.
富斯科  上传这些信息到电脑数据库
Fusco! Upload these specs into the database.
与卫星每十五分钟交叉核对一次
Have the computer cross-check it with overhead satellites
及时更新
every 15 minutes, the van behind it, too.
如果这些车行驶在里约的街巷里
If these vehicles move in the streets of Rio,
我希望能得到消息
I want to know about it.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
一切顺利
Everything is okay.
这个满街跑霍布斯探员何方神圣
Who is this Hobbs? This Federal Agent running around town?
美国人
Some American cowboy.
在我们掌控之中
He's handled.
他杀了我们十六个人
He killed sixteen of our men.
盯紧点儿他
Handle him better.
他要了一个菜鸟巡逻队长做助手
Look... He requested a rookie patrol officer as his assistant.
他们不是问题
They won't be a problem.
-都在这吗  -对
- It's all here?- Yes.
特若图和欧康纳呢  他们在哪
What about Toretto and O'Conner? Where are they?
还没消息
Nothing yet.
但我把人手都派出去找他们了
But I have all our officers searching.
这还不够
Not good enough.
悬赏缉拿
Put a price on their heads.
出个高价
High enough...
让城里每双眼睛都找给我找
...to get every pair of eyes in the city searching for them.
警署内部图
The beauty of public offices?
公共档案室
Public records.
这是他们放钱的地方
This is where he's keeping the money.
保险箱在证物室里
The vault in the evidence room.
麻烦大家注意一下
Um. Uh, yeah. Can I get everyone's attention,
这边  耽误会儿
right here, for a second?
我们正在讨论如何闯入警察局
We're talking about breaking into a police station.
你们听说过这些词吗
Is anyone listening to those words?
警察叔叔
Anybody? Popo?
条子  雷子  当兵的
Five-O. One-time. Pigs.
都是我们的死对头
People we don't like.
警察局的设计  就是让人进去出不来
You know, police stations are designed to keep people in, not out.
所以我们要秘密行动
That's why it's a stealth mission.
没等人反应过来  我们就完活儿了
We'll be in and out before they even know we were there.
我们需要了解那里面的情况
Well, we'll need to get eyes in there.
至少要知道这金库有多大
At least to find out the make and model of that vault.
这大金库...
So the vault and then, so...
很疯狂
it's crazy.
谁适合干这些
Who's supposed to do all this?
你们什么意思
What do you mean?
为什么是我
Why me?
因为你最会说话
Because you got the biggest mouth.
太对了
That's for damn sure.
你好美女
Hello, beautiful.
性感的小酒窝
Look at those dimples. Sexy, sexy.
眼镜真可爱  在哪买的
Love those glasses. Where did you get them from?
镜框是古琦的吗
Are those like Gucci frames or something?
不会英语吗
No English?
不  该死
No, no, no. Damn.
你谁呀
How are you, sir?
美国联邦调查局特工欧康纳
Special Agent O'Conner. US Federal Bureau of Investigation.
你白种人吗
It says Caucasian.
那个  这是晒黑的  晒的
That's a tan. You know, a tan?
你看  我负责这个案子
Look, I'm working this
有些证物要放到证物室
case and I got some evidence here to be held.
但是我要先进去检查你的储存设备
But I need to get in and check your storage facility first.
不行
Nope.
我知道你非常敬业
Look, I know you're a true professional,
我敬佩你  都是真心话
and I respect you, I promise.
你有时也锻炼吧
You know, it looks like you work out a little bit, too.
能举起三百五十磅吗
What do you bench, about 350?
该死
Ah, Shit.
我也只是奉命而已
Look, I'm just trying to do my job, man.
我的头儿让我来确保东西都安全
My boss sent me here to just make sure that everything was safe.
都很安全
It will be safe.
好吧  那你能让我进去简单看一眼吗
Let me just come in and take a quick peek.
不行
Nope.
通融一下伙计  放兄弟一马吧
Come on, man. Hook a brother up, please?
不行  你才不是我兄弟
Nope. And you're not my brother.
同父异母的兄弟
Brother from another mother?
听好了
Look!
未经授权任何人不能进入
No one enters the facility but authorized evidence personnel.
少耽误工夫
Now stop wasting my time.
我要给大使馆打电话了
I'm going to call the embassy.
别别别  没事了
No,no,no! No, we're good.
没必要打电话  不至于
We don't need to call them. For what? We're good.
给你  东西放这了 没事了
Here, I got the box. We're all good.
我保证  非常感谢
I promise you. Thank you so much for your time.
我发誓如果我在玻璃那一面
Swear to God, if you were on the other side of that glass
我就打爆你的脸  好好表示一下
I'd bust your damn face in. Now translate that.
完活儿
It's done. See, I think I
我当特工比你强
make a better special agent than you ever did.
那要看你哪方面更特一点
Well, that depends on how you define "Special."
各位  该看好戏了
Come on, now. Let's see what we got.
别闹
Not funny.
好吧
All right, come on.
你还是不会开车
Dawg, you still can't drive.
看吧 现在我知道你为什么总出事故了
Now, I see why you're always getting into accidents.
你连辆破遥控车都开不好
You can't even drive a damn remote control car.
你马上闭嘴
I'm going to need you to shut up right now.
-才不  -闭嘴
- I'm not going to shut up. - Shut up.
快把他嘴上的堵上
Strap him in his safety belt, man.
给我遥控器  往左
Give me the remote, dawg. Go left.
左边好像有东西
It looks like something
那是什么
right over there to the left. What is that?
What is that?
找到了
Bingo.
这是什么  六乘六的吗
What is that, six-by-six?
八乘十二的
Eight-by-twelve.
七乘十二
Seven-by-twelve.
十八英寸厚的加固钢板
Fitted with 18-inch-thick steel reinforced walls
用绝缘铜芯线抵御高温焊枪
with a insulated copper core to protect against thermal lance.
先进的三级电子锁
A Class-3 electronic lock with a surefire Griffin retumbler
和生物掌纹扫描系统
and a biometric palm scanner.
十倍于顶级线路安全设计
Ten tons of top-of-the-line security.
你怎么知道的这么清楚
Do I want to know how you know all that?
谁都有过去  欧康纳
I had a life before you knew me, O'Conner.
这个以后再说
Let's just leave it at that, all right?
她可真漂亮
She is a beauty, though, man.
是褒义的漂亮吗
A "Beauty" As in "Good"?
漂亮的意思是  她很难搞定
"Beauty" As in, she's going to start off playing hard to get.
而且  不管我怎样爱抚她
Then, no matter how much I caress her,
怎样爱她
no matter how much I love her,
最终还是不会从了我
in the end, she still ain't going to give up that ass.
大家都说你炸错了管道
Two to one says you blow the wrong pipe.
你为什么总抱怨呢
Yo, why you got to be so negative all the time, man?
我没啊
I ain't negative.
我就是坚信你会把事情搞糟
I'm just positive you're going to mess it up.
下次如果没有电梯的话我绝对不来
I'm telling you, man, you got issues.
你要学会放松
You need to learn to relax, loco.
你最好快点  时间不到一分钟了
You better hurry up, we got less than a minute.
为什么你总把时间设置的这么短
Why do you always set the timer so short?
希望你知道要往哪走
I hope you know where you're going.
我明白  放松  放松
I got this. Relax, man.
放松
Relax.
警局
...A police station.
放松
Relax.
你炸药又用多了
You used too much explosive! Again.
多少
Too much, too little...
都一样
it's all the same.
这又是你从监狱图书馆
That's some Buddha shit you
学的狗屁佛家理论吧
learned from a book in the prison library, isn't it?
你在墙上干的事
And what you're doing there on the wall...
也是从那本书上学的吧
You got that from the same book, huh?
你又抱怨了
You're so negative, bro.
给个亮
Can I have some light?
收到  收到了
Got it. We got it!
好的  我们收到四个探头的信号
Yeah, we're looking at four cameras.
又是些高端的光学仪器
Yo, that's some high-end shit, too. Marker optics.
每十秒来回摆动一次
Hundred-degree field-of-view. Ten seconds oscillation.
不是吧  摆动太快了
Yeah, that's a narrow window, man.
我们不能用静态图片代替吗
Can't we just tap in and replace the image?
不行  它是和系统同步的
No, it's hooked into a digital sync.
肯定会被识别出来
They would know we were in the system.
最好就是一闪而过
The best we can do is peek.
我们得用非常快的车来干这件事
We're going to need some real fast cars to get through this.
而且不只车要快
Not just fast.
还需要高超的驾驶技巧和练习
You got a hard right and a hairpin.
必须开得敏捷又灵活
We're going to need something agile.
你们几个画出一个跑道
You guys mock up a track.
欧康纳
O'Conner.
咱们去找几辆车
Let's go get some cars.
爽
Nice.
舒服  真舒服
Home sweet home.
那个
Or that.
那辆怎么样  引擎声相当完美
How about that? All motor, no tuning issues.
我一直想要一辆那样的
I always wanted one of those.
恩威达大赛三年的纪录保持者
Held the record on the Avenida three years running.
该死
Damn, bro...
你来这真是自找麻烦  特若图
You got a lot of balls to bring your problems here, Toretto.
还带着个条子
Not to mention a cop.
咱们可以保持低调
Yeah, we can keep that on the low.
都说很多人在找你们俩
Word on the street is a lot of people are looking for you two.
啥
What?
你没想过我们会认出你们吗
You didn't think we'd recognize you?
你们有什么车
No, we're kind of counting on it.
那辆小跑可能走街串巷吃得开
That little coupe may run the streets around here,
但是那位大哥还从没看过别的车的尾灯呢
but that monster has never seen a set of tail lights.
马上就会了
Even Well, she's about to.
多米尼克・特若图  来我这赛车了
Dominic Toretto's ride in my garage.
那辆车  是辆不错的战利品
Now that... will be a nice trophy.
来吧  传奇
Let's go, legend.
以车赌车
Car for car.
Car for car?
想要  就来比比
You want it, come and get it.
大伙瞧瞧
Let's see what they got.
真的假的
Really?
你在哪弄到的  波巴的市场里吗
Where did you get that from? Papa Smurf?
来吧欧康纳  使出你的看家本事
Okay, O'Conner, give it your best shot.
怎么样
How was that one?
探头照到你了
Camera caught you.
-什么  -没错  找到了
- What? - Yeah, it still caught you.
看来我得开得更快才行
Man, I was milking the hell out of that thing, too.
我们需要更快的车
We're going to need a faster car.
我需要那笔钱
I want my money. Come on, man.
来吧  看这个
Let's get it! Watch this.
这就能解释你为什么不开车
That's exactly why your ass ain't been driving.
我想  我恋爱了
I think I'm in love.
技术绝对一流
That was real solid work.
但是三号探头还是抓到你了
I think Camera 3 still caught you, though.
再来一遍
Let's do it again.
这是你订制的存钱罐吗
That's the piggy bank you ordered.
太搞笑了
You're kidding me. Yep.
你从哪里搞到的
Where in the hell did y'all get one of these?
好吧  谁都有过去
Well, we had a life before you met us.
好吧  我来搞定电子锁
All right, I'll get to work on the electronic tumbler
但是还有个问题
but there's still another problem.
掌纹扫描系统
Palm scanner.
没有雷耶斯的掌纹
And without Reyes' handprint,
胡迪尼[世界最著名魔术师]都打不开
Houdini himself couldn't open this bitch.
你怎么知道一定是雷耶斯本人的掌纹
How do you know it's Reyes' handprint?
如果里面的一亿美元是你的
You got $100 million in a safe.
你会用别人的掌纹来做密码吗
You going to put somebody else's handprint on it?
这玩意要弄死你了
That shit is eating you alive.
试试
You check that.
-试试  -闭嘴
- Yo, check that. - Shut up!
我们怎么搞到雷耶斯的掌纹
How are we supposed to get Reyes' handprint?
韩
Han.
你来
You're up.
没问题  小事一桩
Sure. Nothing like the easy stuff.
我也去  我开车
Let's go. I'll drive.
-有六个保镖  -七个
- I make six bodyguards. - Seven.
你觉得那个一脸怪相的人是游客吗
You think that guy with a fanny pack is a tourist?
你在军队待了多久
So, how long were you in the army?
你那天用的Jericho 941[手枪型号]
That gun you pulled the other day was a Jericho 941.
快速上膛
Thumb-racking the slide?
摩萨德[以色列情报和特殊使命局]的招式
That was straight-up Mossad.
你戒烟的时候
I got out of the military
我就退伍了
probably the same time you quit smoking.
你吃那么多薯片
The amount of chips you eat,
嘴还闲不住是吗
the way you always have to keep your hands and mouth busy,
你以前一天肯定抽两包
you were a two-pack-a-day man for sure.
无滤嘴的
Unfiltered.
这次没戏
Well, this is a bust.
拿不到雷耶斯的掌纹
We're not going to be able to get his fingerprints out here.
还得多做点侦察  再找几个帮手
We need to do some more recon, call in a couple of extra guys.
或者
Or
有些事儿注定要女人来做
you don't send a man to do a woman's job.
我们能搞定  我保证
We're going to figure this out, I promise you.
怎么了
What's up?
原来你也不是什么正人君子
I thought you were more of a thong man.
弄到掌纹了
We got the print.
在哪
Where?
这太扯了
Okay, that's crazy.
他就拍了一下你的屁股  还是整个抓住
So, did he just slap that ass or did he grab and hold on to it?
这个能用
Hey, this will work.
我看好你哦
I'm impressed.
-行吗  -可以
- Got it? - Got it.
可你还没回答呢
But you still didn't answer the question.
伙计们  有麻烦了
Oh, no. Guys, guys! Guys, we have a problem.
我们都暴露了
The whole team just got burnt.
我们被通缉了
Now we're all wanted.
怎么会
How did this happen?
美国外交安全局已经授权
US Diplomatic Security Service issued the warrants.
霍布斯探员
Agent L. Hobbs.
等等
Hold on one second.
多姆
Hey, Dom.
这人是你在贫民区见过的那个吗
Is that the guy you saw in the favela?
是的
Yeah.
霍布斯是Dss精英特遣队长
Hobbs is the leader of the elite task force for the DSS.
就是说  他很厉害吗
So he's good.
FBI想抓人的时候就派他出马
When the FBI wants to find somebody, that's who they call.
因为他从未失手
Because he never misses his mark.
这家伙是个传奇人物
This guy is Old Testament.
铁血硬汉是他的一贯作风
Blood, bullets, wrath of God. That's his style.
而且此时此刻他正在找我们
And right now he's hunting us?
多姆  我们得加快进度了
Dom, we got to move up our timeline.
好的  但是怎么来
Yeah, but how?
这件事已经很困难了
This thing's already been
如果他再掺合进来
difficult without Wyatt Earp on our asses.
我们需要更多的喘息空间
If anything, we need more room to breathe.
罗曼说的没错
Roman's right.
我们出去透透气
Think we need to get some fresh air.
找到了  70年代的Charger
We've got a hit. '70s Charger.
出发
Let's get a move on!
向安维尼迪拉卡街区东部行驶
Eastbound on Avenida Atlantica.
快快快
Move, move, move, move!
他在前面一个街区停下了
It stopped about a block ahead.
停车  我们步行过去
Park it. We're going on foot.
特若图
Hey, Toretto.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
被捕?
Arrest?
我看不是吧
I don't feel like I'm under arrest.
你觉得呢布莱恩
How about you, Brian?
不  没有
No, not a bit.
一点都没有
Not even a little bit.
我给你们一分钟  看能不能想明白
Just give it a minute. It'll sink in.
我们没杀那些联邦探员  雷耶斯干的
We didn't kill those feds. That was Reyes.
我不管这个
I don't give a shit.
我听命抓两个混蛋归案
I'm just here to bring in two assholes whose names hit my desk.
听起来像真英雄
Yeah, that sounds like a real hero.
真搞笑
That's funny.
这话出自一个警察
From a guy who took the oath of a cop,
他忘掉先前的誓言
then went against everything it stood for.
一个硬汉
Or some wannabe tough guy prick
原来用电棍惩治恶徒
who beat a man half to death with a socket wrench.
还真是条好汉
Yeah, real tough.
现在转身双手放在背后
You turn around and put your hands behind your back.
我不会这么做
I don't think so.
小子  你以为自己有的选吗
Your mistake is thinking you got a goddamn choice, boy.
你搞错了把
And your mistake?
还以为自己在美国啊
Thinking you're in America.
你离家可远着呢
You're a long way from home.
这是巴西
This is Brazil.
算了  头儿  改天吧
Come on, boss. Another day.
算了  今天不是时候
Come on, H, it's a lot of heat.
后会有期  特若图
I'll see you soon, Toretto.
随时奉陪
I look forward to it, cop.
好了
Yep.
追踪器装好了
Tracker's on.
找到了
Got them.
我不明白  来干什么
I don't understand. Why come here?
为了一个二十美元的银饰值得吗
Why risk it all for $20 worth of silver?
它值得
Because it's worth it.
你该逃走
You should run, you know.
霍布斯会抓到你的
Hobbs will find you.
你有一万个理由离开  为什么不呢
You have every reason to leave. Why stay?
你又是为什么呢
Why do you?
我丈夫是个好警员...
My husband was a good police officer.
老实人...
An honest man.
我们青梅竹马
We both grew up here.
两年前  他在街上被谋杀了
Two years ago he was murdered in the street
就在我们家门外
right outside our door.
这里是雷耶斯的地盘  他给大家东西
Reyes owns this favela now. He gives things to people.
而东西不是白给的
But everything has a price.
这里的人们需要一个新的开始
The people here need a new start.
需要自由
They need to be free.
火车上那些人不是你杀的
You didn't kill those men in the train,
对吗
did you?
你现在怎么又相信我了呢
Now, why would you believe anything I would tell you?
她对你来说真的那么特别吗
Was she so special to you?
我以为没有人能够理解
I never thought anyone could understand now much.
但是你懂我了
But you do.
差不多  但还不够好
Close, but not enough.
伙计  时间太短了
Dom, the window is too small, man.
唯一能躲过摄像头的办法就是用隐形车了
Only way we're going to beat the cameras is with invisible cars.
我正好知道这么个地方
And I know just where to get them.
伙计们  出去兜个风吧
Let's take a ride, boys.
别伤着自己
Don't hurt yourself.
我已经好久没有
It's been a while since
驾驶过警车了
I've been behind the wheel of one of these.
我也是第一次坐警车前座
First time I've ever been in the front seat.
罗曼  怎么耽搁这么久
Rome, what took you so long?
我刚打包票你一定会
I thought for sure you'd be
装个铬纺轮还是什么登场的
showing up with some chrome spinners or something.
真搞笑
Real funny.
我赌十万美金
I got $100,000 that says
我比你们都先到下下个路口
I can take you all in the next quarter-mile.
你说的像真有十万块似的
Yeah, your broke ass has got a hundred grand.
如果我们这次干成了  我就有了
If we pull off this job, I will.
下两个红绿灯
The next two lights.
十万块
Hundred thousand.
如果我们这次干砸了  反正也死翘翘了
We don't pull this job off, we're probably dead anyway.
我们赌一百万吧
Let's make it a million.
我赞成  一百万赌四分之一英里
I like that. All right, a million-dollar quarter-mile.
好的
All right, then.
人生只有一次 来吧
You only live once. Let's do it.
多姆  你说呢
What do you say, Dom?
到底要聊天呢还是要赛车
We talking or we racing?
这次别作弊了啊
Just don't cheat this time.
你就是不能忘了这茬
Got to let that go.
还是老样子  罗曼
Typical, Roman.
我需要这笔钱  我赢定了
I'm going to get this money. I'm hungry.
别让我赢得太容易  伙计们
Don't make it too easy for me, boys.
没门
No!
那可没准  多姆
Not this time, Dom.
加把劲儿  布莱恩
You got to want it, Brian.
我赢了  赢了
Yeah! Owned you! Owned you!
-开得不错  欧康纳  -承让
- Good race, O'Conner. - Thanks, Dom.
你们知道我等这天多久了吗
Do you know how long I've been waiting for that shit?
我就说  他没看出来吧
I told you he didn't see it.
你没看出来吗
Your man right there?
他最后关头松了油门
He let off the throttle at the line.
你没赢  他让你的
You didn't do nothing. He let you win.
胡扯
Bullshit.
-文森  你要做什么 -别说话  有人跟踪
- Vince, what are you doing? - Quiet! They've been tracking you.
我知道那个女的在这
I know she's here!
去找
Find her!
快去
Go!Go!Go!
没事  等等
It's okay. Wait!
雷耶斯的人在市场埋伏我
Reyes' guys were waiting for me at the market.
文森救了我
Vince saved my life.
饿不饿
You hungry?
-正好饿了  -不错
- Yeah, sure. - Good.
今天还算客气
Because you're saying grace.
谢了  文森
Thanks, Vince.
你把它烤焦了
Yo, you burned it!
我妈就这么弄  放松
Yo, this is how my momma does it. Relax.
是的  但是你妈是世上最差的厨子
Yeah, but your mom is the worst cook in the world.
不许说我老妈
Yo, don't you be talking about my momma.
干一个  生活不错
Yeah, come on, baby. Who's good living?
干杯  干杯  干杯
To you, bro. Cheers, cheers, cheers.
我们在巴西  活的还不错
So, we in Brazil. It's the good life.
你有  有了一千还是一千一百多万后
So, you got a little more than $10 or $11 million coming.
打算怎么花
What you going to do with your money?
-我吗 -是的
- Me? - Yeah.
事实上  我一直想着
Actually, man, I been
回家开一个修车厂
thinking about opening up a garage back home.
顾客把车开来
Place where people can bring their cars and
只赚一点点就好
not get completely ripped off.
你明白不
You know what I mean?
-真的吗 -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
那么  你的梦想就是白天干活
So, your dream is to start a day job?
这  这真蠢  伙计  为什么
That's stupid. Like, why would...
不...这一点也不蠢  我喜欢干这个
No, it's not stupid at all. I love what I do.
那有啥意思
That don't make no sense to me.
你们想知道我怎么花吗
I know what I'm going to do with my money.
为我男人找个厨师班
Buying some cooking lessons for my man.
看到没
See? See?
你又开始抱怨这个了
There you go with that negativity, man.
你了解我  我不在乎钱
You know me. Money ain't a goddamn thing.
光交学费  学不会做饭
It's going to take a little more than money to learn how to cook.
那真糟糕
That's horrible.
我听说动物收容所
But I heard they was looking
正在找个厨子
for a chef down at this animal shelter.
你想不想
You might want to...
我认识经理
I know the manager.
你好  多姆
Hey, Dom.
听着
Listen.
我知道你明天要干一票
I know that you're all set for this job tomorrow,
如果还缺人手
but if you need an extra man, I could...
麦克  你也有份
You're in.
一家人不说两家话
There's always room for family.
谢谢
Thank you.
吃点东西去
Get something to eat.
好
Yeah.
米亚称它为诅咒
Can you believe Mia calls this a curse?
她或许是对的
She might be right.
你真的挺喜欢做这个的
You really like doing that stuff, huh?
生死攸关之时
When your life is on the line
只能靠自己
that's when you learn about yourself.
这是个公平交易
That's a fair deal.
距离我们人生最大的庆祝
We're less than 24 hours
不到二十四小时了
from the biggest celebration of our life.
你们得充充电  这是很严肃的事
Y'all need a refill. This is serious stuff.
-不了  -喝一个
- No, I'm good. - Cheers, baby.
不  不用了  不了  谢谢
I'm good. No, thank you.
不  她不能喝
No, she can't.
什么意思  她不能喝
What do you mean? She can't.
What do you mean she can't? What is...
你不是在开玩笑吧
Are you serious right now?
这就是你让他跑赢你的原因吗
Is that the reason you let him beat you in the quarter-mile?
-是给宝宝的礼物  -才不是
- That was a baby gift. - No, that's messed up.
你说什么都是我赢了
No, you're not taking that from me.
等等  等等  等一下
Wait, wait, hold on a second.
他是拍了一下你的屁股  还是整个抓住
So, did he just smack the ass or did he grab and hold on to it?
哪一种
Which One was it?
-恭喜  -谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
为什么藏着不告诉我们
How can you keep this a secret?
你小子都有儿子了
Crazy, huh?  It's your boy.
给宝宝的礼物
Baby gift, huh?
我不知道他们在说什么
I have no idea what they're talking about.
致敬
Toast
钱财乃身外之物
Money will come and go. We know that.
生命中最宝贵永远是
But the most important thing
这个房间里的你们
in life will always be the people in this room.
此时
Right here.
此地
Right now.
我准备好了
I'm all set.
桑托斯  都好了吗
Yo, Santos. Van good?
是的  我随时就绪  兄弟
You know we're always good, bro.
霍布斯他们在城市另一头
Hobbs is on the other side of the city.
这是最佳时机
We're not going to get a better window.
来吧  伙计们  该我们上场了
Okay, guys, it's show time!
第一队就位  出发
First team in position, let's go.
快点  出发
Come on, let's do this.
多姆
Hey, Dom.
我会照顾米亚的
I got eyes on Mia.
莫斯科  巴厘  果阿邦  香港
Moscow, Bali, Goa, Hong Kong.
他们有什么共同点
And what do they all have in common?
不能引渡
No extradition.
我们还有一小时就可以去了
We're one hour away from the rest of our lives.
警察
Cops!
快点  跑
Come on. Go.
你刚真是大错特错了
You just made a big mistake.
找到追踪芯片是费了我点时间
Took me a while to find that tracking chip.
但是  找接收器可不用那么久
But not as long to flip the receiver.
特若图  你完了
You're going down, Toretto.
老子奉陪到底
I'm right here.
-多姆  退后 -我来搞定
- Dom! Stand back. - I got this.
-住手  -多姆  住手
- Pull off! - Dom! Please, stop!
多姆
Dom!
我们正在回来的路上
We're coming in now.
派警队去机场接我们
Have the marshals meet us at the airport when we land.
有埋伏
Ambush!
威尔克斯  反击  搞定他们
Wilkes, suppression fire. Shut them down.
掩护我
Stagger-step. Cover me.
看着那边
Watch them!
放开我们
Cut us loose!
快点  放开我们
Come on! Cut us loose!
-都上来了吗  -开车
- We're good? - Yeah, let's go, let's go!
多姆
Hey, Dom.
你还没见过我儿子
You've got to meet my son.
尼克
Nico.
我会见到的
I will.
他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
我们用你的名字给他命名的
You know, we named him after you.
多米尼克
"Dominic."
我向你保证  文森
You've got my word, Vince.
你一直是我的兄弟
You were always my brother.
我帮你养儿子
I got eyes on Nico now.
我们得走了  没有多少时间了
We need to move. We don't have that much time.
我订了趟航班跑路
I got us a flight out.
五小时后离开里约热内卢
We can leave Rio in the rearview in the next five hours.
不是逃跑
Not to run away.
而是完成计划
To finish the job.
多姆  你疯了吗  我们办不到
Are you crazy, Dom? We can't.
这无疑是在自杀
It's a suicide mission.
你兄弟还躺在那里尸骨未寒
That's your man over there on the table.
计划破产了
The plan is busted!
都是胡扯  雷耶斯知道我们要去
This is bullshit, man. Reyes knows we're coming!
他说的对
He's right.
他们增派了三倍的人手在警察局
They tripled the detail at the police station.
这将是一场血战
it's going to be a wall of gunfire.
不能轻易饶了雷耶斯
Reyes doesn't get away with this.
这是个陷阱  伙计
It's a trap, man.
你早知道
You know that.
多姆  听他们的吧
Dom, listen to them.
趁还有机会  逃吧  离开里约
Run, before it's too late. Leave Rio.
你就自由了
You can be free.
逃跑不会自由
Running ain't freedom.
你应该明白的
You should know that.
你们自己有权决定去留
You know you're all free to make your own choices.
我入伙
I'm in.
特若图  我和你一起去
I'll ride with you, Toretto.
最起码杀了那个狗娘养的
At least until we kill that son of a bitch.
多姆  那计划是什么
So what's the plan, Dom?
想藏也藏不住了
We can't just go sneaking around anymore.
我们不藏
We don't sneak.
他唯一在意的就是他的钱
The only thing he cares about is his money.
我们控制了钱
We pull that,
也就控制了他
we pull him.
看到了吗
See?
全部警员出动
I called in every cop on our payroll.
万无一失
We're covered.
每个入口都有人守卫
We've got every entrance covered with weapons teams.
即使上帝也不可能拿走您的钱
God Himself couldn't get at your money if He wanted to.
我可不担心上帝
God isn't my worry.
准备好了吗
You ready?
准备好了
I'm ready.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
他们来打劫了
They're taking the vault!
-什么  -金库
- What? - The vault!
跟我来  快点
Follow me! Quickly!
让我过去
Let me through!
不许动
Don't move!
趴下
Stay down.
米亚  路况
Call it out, Mia!
直走  两个街区
You've got a straight shot for two blocks.
-右转  -好
- Go right.- Got it.
不出意料
Well, the plan is working.
里约所有的警车都在追你们
You guys have every corrupt cop in Rio on your tail.
你们得跑快一点
You have to move fast.
最佳落点在哪里
What's the best route?
向前行驶半英里到的卢福
Okay, keep going straight another half-mile onto Rua Fonseca,
然后左转
and then go left.
行不通
That ain't going to work.
多姆  前面有钉子  有钉子
Spikes ahead, Dom. We got spikes!
往右开
We're going right!
不行  太挤了  过不去
No, it's too tight, we're not going to fit.
没选择了  立刻
We've got no choice. Now!
狗屎
Shit!
真要命
Holy shit!
伙计们  我都听到动静了
Guys, I am hearing all this chatter.
你们把银行拖出来了啊
Did you just take out a bank?
来了两辆
Two inbound!
好的  你们左侧有个巷子
All right, there's an alley coming up on your left.
好的  知道了
Yeah, I got it.
王八蛋
You little bastard!
不错  多姆  这里右转
All right, good job, Dom. Right-hander, right here, right-hander.
南边追过去一大队人马
Guys, there's a big group coming at you from the south.
你们想想办法
You have to do something now!
分开两侧
Hey, go wide.
左侧障碍清除
You're all clear on the left.
下午好  警官
Good afternoon, officer!
请您出示驾照
License and registration, please!
帅呆了
Yes! This is big-boy stuff!
右侧障碍清除
We're clear on the right.
厉害
Oh, man.
谢谢伙计们
Thanks, guys.
随叫随到
Any time.
一会儿见
I'll see you on the other side.
你们只有十秒钟
You guys just carved out a 10-second window.
抓紧时间
Make it count!
齐齐  跟紧他们
Zizi, stay on them.
在桥上他们甩不掉我们的
They can't outrun us on the bridge.
该死
Shit.
无路可逃吧
They have no way out.
不
No!
他们人太多了
There's too many of them.
我们没办法甩掉的
Hey, there's too many of them. We're not going to make it.
是的  我们甩不掉
You're right, we aren't.
甩掉你可以
You are.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
甩掉金库  离开那里
Just let the vault go. Get out of there.
布莱恩  你是有孩子的人了
You're a father now, Brian.
我不会丢下你的  你按计划来
No, I'm not leaving you. Now you stick with the plan!
计划本来就如此
It was always the plan.
照顾好米亚
Take care of Mia.
多姆  你现在听我说
Dom, you listen to me now. Okay?
立刻切断绳索
You cut loose right now.
他要干什么
Hey, what is he doing?
我们要抓到他了
We've got him!
封闭大桥
Close down the bridge!
想想办法  混蛋
Do something, asshole!
杀掉他  妈的
Kill him, dammit!
干掉他  快点
Kill him now!
不是让你别回头吗
I thought I told you to go on.
没错  但我的干完这笔
Yeah, I had to make a call.
救我
Help me.
狗杂种  这枪是为了我兄弟们
That's for my team, you son of a bitch.
简直一团糟啊
It's a hell of a mess.
是的
Yeah, it is.
我不可能放你们走
You know I can't let you two go.
这与我的职责不符
I ain't made that way.
我给你二十四小时的时间
The way I see it, you've earned yourselves 24 hours.
但是钱要留下
The money stays, though.
如果我是你  我会好好利用这个时间
If I were you, I'd use the time.
把该处理的事情都处理好
Make peace with whatever demons you got left.
到了明天
Because come tomorrow,
我就去抓你们
I will find you.
特若图
Toretto!
后会有期
I'll see you soon.
不  后会无期
No, you won't.
谢啦  伙计们
Thanks, guys.
一会见
I'll see you on the other side.
你们只有十秒钟
You guys just carved out a 10 second window.
抓紧时间
Make it count!
拜托  宝贝
Come on, baby.
别为难我
Don't be mean.
拜托
Come on.
给罗莎和尼克  再见  多姆叔叔
For Rosa and Nico. See you soon,
你确定要这么做吗
You sure about this?
你知道的  当然
You know I am.
你不必如此的
You don't need to do this.
别烦我了
Just leave me alone.
伙计  我不是反对你
Bro, I'm not trying to be negative, but casinos
只是赌场
are the kinds of places
就是专门坑我们这种人的地方
designed to take money from guys like you and me.
等我赢了
When I win here I'm buying
给你够吃一辈子的抗抑郁药
you a lifetime supply of antidepressants.
不要把一千万都押红色
You don't put ten million on red!
够了
Enough already.
押黑色
You put it on black.
停止下注
No more bets.
这边  甜心
Right this way, my dear.
待在这里  我马上回来
You stay right here, I'll be right back.
这就是你的梦想了啊
So, this is your dream, huh?
这对我足够了
It's enough for me, man.
看来你也实现梦想了
I take it that's your dream.
当然  怎么样...
Absolutely. What up, boy? What's going on?
-你不错啊  -是的
- You good? - Yes, yes.
你知道多疯狂吗
You know what's crazy?
这车全球只有四辆
There's only four of those cars in the whole world.
我拥有西半球唯一的一辆
Yeah, I got the only one in the Western Hemisphere.
我给了阿布扎比酋长一个无法拒绝的高价
I made a sheikh in Abu Dhabi an offer he could not refuse.
那个姑娘也不错
Huh. That's a nice lady you got there, too.
那是当然
Absolutely. What's happening?
伙计  我们要出发了  走吧
We got to go, man. Let's do this.
好的  我要开车
Okay, I'll drive.
这个吗  拜托 伙计 别...没门
In that? Come on, man, no way.
不  不是这个
No, no. Not in this.
那个
In that.
你不是在开玩笑吧
Are you serious right now?
伙计  这太疯狂了
Man, this is crazy!
是的  这意味着
Yes, I guess that means
在西半球有两辆这个车了
there are two in the Western Hemisphere, huh?
现在你个大忽悠要说点什么
What's your smart ass got to say now?
我们可以一直结伴出去拉风了
You know what? We can always shine together, baby.
换衣服  伙计  我们要出发了
Get dressed, man, we got things to do!
现在去哪里
So, where to now?
柏林
我也不知道
I don't know.
从没去过马德里
Never been to Madrid.
我以为你会去东京
I thought you wanted to go to Tokyo.
我们会去的...
We'll get there.
最后去...
Eventually.
没想到你会来
Nice surprise.
疯狂
Crazy, right?
这是我见过的老妹最幸福的时候
This is the happiest I've ever seen my sister.
因为自由
It's because we're free.
我想再比一次
You know, I want another shot.
是吗
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
没有赌注  没有别人
No wagers, nobody else.
就你和我  只此一次
Just you and me, once and for all.
你确定能承受失败的打击吗
You sure you can handle the disappointment?
你呢
Are you?
好吧  欧康纳
All right, O'Conner.
后面还有哦!
看看你有多大本领
Let's see what you got.
外交保安局总部  华盛顿
Diplomatic security service headquarters - Washington, d.C.
你看下这个
You need to look at that.
柏林  今晨三点
Berlin. 3:00 a.m. This morning.
一队车手抢劫了一辆军用运输车
A team of drivers hijacked a military convoy.
-特若图吗  -不是
- Toretto? - Nope.
不感兴趣
I ain't interested.
不  你会感兴趣  继续看
Yes, you are. Keep looking.
相信活见鬼了吗
Do you believe in ghosts?